Guide to the Margaret S. Mahler Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1924-1984; Series III; 16 linear feet (36 boxes)
  - Manuscripts: Published
    - The Psychological Birth of the Human Infant
      - Anni Bergman Material section II, Chapter 2, 1972 December (Box 85, Folder 1375)
      - References Sections I, II, and III, undated (Box 86, Folder 1376)
      - References\General, undated (Box 86, Folder 1377)
      - Notes\General, undated (Box 86, Folder 1378)
      - Notes, undated (Box 86, Folder 1379)
        Titles and Subtitles
        Preface
        Part I, Chapter 1
      - Notes, 1972, 1973, undated (Box 86, Folder 1380)
        Introduction
        Section I
      - Notes/Sections II and III, 1973 (Box 86, Folder 1381)
      - Notes/Section IV, undated (Box 86, Folder 1382)
      - Notes/Section V, 1973, undated (Box 86, Folder 1383)
      - Notes Anni Bergman, undated (Box 86, Folder 1384)
      - Notes Body-Ego "Core-Boundaries", undated (Box 86, Folder 1385)
      - Notes Children, 1971-1973, undated (Box 86, Folder 1386)
      - Notes Mahler's Writings, 1965-1972 (Box 86, Folder 1387)
      - Notes Other Author's Writings, undated (Box 86, Folder 1388)
      - Notes Other Author's Writings, undated (Box 87, Folder 1389-1390)
      - Notes Unidentified, 1969-1973, undated (Box 87, Folder 1391-1392)
      - "Miscellaneous Usable Pages -To Be Edited", 1973 January (Box 87, Folder 1393)
      - Book Galleys, 1974 (Box 87, Folder 1394)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1974, undated (Box 87, Folder 1395)
      - Reviews, 1973-1977, undated (Box 87, Folder 1396)
      - French Translation-Turgis, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 1397)
    - Selected Papers of Margaret S. Mahler
      - Volume 1-Infantile Psychoses and Allied Conditions Chapters 1-6, 1978 (Box 88, Folder 1398)
      - Volume 1-Infantile Psychoses and Allied Conditions Chapters 7-13, Appendices, 1978 (Box 88, Folder 1399)
      - Volume 2-On Separation-Individuation Chapters 1-10, 1978 July (Box 88, Folder 1400)
      - Volume 2-On Symbiosis-Individuation Chapters 11-14, 1978 July (Box 88, Folder 1401)
      - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 88, Folder 1402)
  - Manuscripts: Unpublished
    - Psychoanalysis with Children Notes, 1954 (Box 88, Folder 1403)
    - Psychoanalysis with Children Correspondence, 1954 (Box 88, Folder 1404)
    - Theory and Techniques of Child Analysis Notes, 1955-1962 (Box 88, Folder 1405)
  - Volumes
    - On Human Symbiosis and the Vicissitudes of Individuation, Volume 1: Infantile Psychosis NY: International Universities Press, 1968 (Box 88, Folder 1406)
    - On Human Symbiosis and the Vicissitudes of Individuation, Volume 1: Infantile Psychosis London: Hogarth Press and the Institute of Psycho-Analysis, 1968 (Box 88, Folder 1407)
    - Symbiosis Humana: Las Vicisitudes dela Individuacion: Psicosis. Infantil Mexico: Joaquin Mortiz, 1972 (Box 89, Folder 1408)
    - Le Psicosi Infantili: Simbiosi Umana eVicende Dell' Individuazione Milano: Editore Boringhieri, 1972 (Box 89, Folder 1409)
    - Symbiose and Individuation Band I: Psychosen im Fröhen Kindesalter Stuttgart: Ernst Klett Verlag, 1972 (Box 89, Folder 1410)
    - Symbiose Humaine et Individuation Psychose Infantile Paris: Payot, 1973 (Box 89, Folder 1411)
    - Symbiose und Individuation Band I: Psychosen im Fröhen Kindesalter Stuttgart: Klett-Cotta, 1973 (Box 89, Folder 1412)
    - The Psychological Birth of the Human Infant Japanese Translation Tokyo: Reimei Shobo, 1975 (Box 89, Folder 1413)
    - O Nascimiento Psicologico da Crianga: Simbiose e Individuagao Rio de Janiero: Zahar Editores, 1977 (Box 89, Folder 1414)
    - E1 Nascimiento Psicologico del Infante Humano Buenos Aires: Marymar, 1977 (Box 90, Folder 1415)
    - Die Psychische Geburt des Menschen: Symbiose und Individuation Frankfurt am Main: S. Fischer Verlag, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 1416)
    - La Nascita Psicologica del Bambino Milano: Editore Boringhieri, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 1417)
    - Die Psychische Geburt des Menschen:Svmbiose and Individuation Frankfurt am Main: Fischer Taschenbuch Verlag, 1980 (Box 91, Folder 1418)
    - La Naissance Psychologique de L'être Humaine Paris: Payot, 1980 (Box 91, Folder 1419)
    - Barnets Psykika Födelse:Symbios och Individuation Stockholm: Svensk Upplaga Bokförlaget Natur och Kultur, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 1420)
    - The Selected Papers of Margaret S.Mahler, Volume One: Infantile Psychosis and EarlyContributions NY: Jason Aronson, 1979 (Box 91, Folder 1421)
    - The Selected Papers of Margaret S.Mahler, Volume Two: Separation-Individuation NY: Jason Aronson, 1979 (Box 92, Folder 1422)
    - Oneness and Separateness: From Infantto Individual, by Louise J. Kaplan, Ph. D. NY: Simon and Schuster Foreword, 1978 (Box 92, Folder 1423)
    - Oneness and Separateness: From Infantto Individual, by Louise J. Kaplan, Ph.d. NY: Touchstone Books Foreword, 1979 (Box 92, Folder 1424)
  - Works in Progress.
    - "Omnipotence", 1974 (Box 92, Folder 1425)
    - "Vulnerable Child", 1975 (Box 92, Folder 1426)
    - "Theory Paper", 1974-1977 (Box 92, Folder 1427)
    - "Peter Pan", 1976-1978 (Box 92, Folder 1428)
    - "Borderline and Pathological Narcissism", 1976 (Box 93, Folder 1429)
    - "Constructive Use of Aggression", 1976-1981, undated (Box 93, Folder 1430-1432)
    - "Emergence of Self", 1980 (Box 93, Folder 1433)
    - "Hatching", 1980 (Box 93, Folder 1434)
    - "Paranoia", 1981 (Box 93, Folder 1435)
    - "Separation-Anxiety", 1981 (Box 93, Folder 1436)
    - Dan Stern Material, 1981 March (Box 93, Folder 1437)
    - "Emotional Concepts of Margaret S. Mahler", undated (Box 93, Folder 1438)
    - "Seminal Concepts of Margaret S. Mahler", undated (Box 93, Folder 1439)
    - Unidentified, 1984, 1985, undated (Box 94, Folder 1440-1442)
    - Workbook, 1971-1980 (Box 94, Folder 1443-1447)
    - Notes on Schizophrenia, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 1448)
    - Notes, 1976, 1984, undated (Box 94, Folder 1449-1450)
  - Bibliographies
    - "Symbiosis and Symbiotic Psychosis", 1966 (Box 95)
    - "On Human Symbiosis and the Vicissitudes of Individuation", 1967 (Box 95)
    - Freud Anniversary Lecture, 1970 (Box 95)
    - "The Current Status of Infantile Neurosis", 1973 (Box 95)
    - "Emergence of the Self", 1981 (Box 95)
    - Work-in-Progress, 1980-1981 (Box 95)
    - Unidentified (6), undated (Box 95)
    - Bibliographic References, 1943-1972 (Box 95)
    - General (3), 1924-1973 (Box 96)
    - General: Unpublished, 1947-1970 (Box 96)
    - "Adaptation and Defense", 1967 (Box 96)
    - "On Human Symbiosis and the Vicissitudes of Individuation", 1967 (Box 96)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 96)
    - General, 1943-1969, 1973-1980 (Box 97, Folder 1451-1452)
    - "Adaptation and Defense", 1967 (Box 97, Folder 1453)
    - "Autism and Symbiosis…", 1958 (Box 97, Folder 1453)
    - "Childhood Schizophrenia…", 1954 (Box 97, Folder 1453)
    - "On Infantile Precursors of the Influencing Machine", 1959 (Box 97, Folder 1453)
    - "Unidentified", undated (Box 97, Folder 1453)
    - Bibliographic References, 1965-1972, 1978 (Box 97, Folder 1454)
  - Oral Histories and Memoirs
    - Columbia University Sverdlof, Bluma
      - Final Copy, 1977 (Box 97, Folder 1455)
      - Interviews, 1977 (Box 97, Folder 1456)
      - Drafts, 1974 (Box 97, Folder 1457)
      - Interviews, 1969 October-November (Box 97, Folder 1458)
      - Notes, undated (Box 97, Folder 1459)
    - Interview by Milton J. E. Senn, M.D., 1977 December (Box 97, Folder 1460)
    - Interview of Mahler and Selma Kramer by Darlene M. Levy, Circa 1980 (Box 97, Folder 1461)
    - Interview with Nancy Chodorow, 1981 March 26 (Box 97, Folder 1462)
    - Interview by Doris Nagel, 1981 April (Box 98, Folder 1463)
    - Interview with Doris Nagel; A. Schlesinger, editor, 1981 (Box 98, Folder 1464)
    - Interview by Joseph Noshpitz, M.D., 1981 May (Box 98, Folder 1465-1466)
    - Memoirs of Margaret S. Mahler: Paul Stepansky, editor
      - Suggestions, 1981 (Box 98, Folder 1467)
      - Outlines, 1980, 1981, undated (Box 98, Folder 1468)
      - Chronology, 1980 May, 1897-1980 (Box 98, Folder 1469-1470)
      - Notes, 1980, 1981 (Box 98, Folder 1471)
      - Drafts-Odenburg, Budapest, 1980, 1981 (Box 98, Folder 1472)
      - Draft-Munich, 1980 (Box 99, Folder 1473)
      - Drafts-Jena, Heidelberg, 1980, 1981 (Box 99, Folder 1474)
      - Drafts-Vienna, 1980-1981 (Box 99, Folder 1475-1476)
      - Drafts-England, 1981 (Box 99, Folder 1477)
      - Drafts-United States, 1980, 1981 (Box 99, Folder 1478-1480)
    - Hungarian Oral History Project Columbia University, 1983 July (Box 99, Folder 1481)
    - Interview with Judith R. Smith, undated (Box 99, Folder 1482)
- Professional Associations, 1950-1984; Series IV; 5.5 linear feet (13 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the corporate name of the association. The bulk of the material dates from the 1970s.
  - American Academy of Child Psychiatry
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1961, 1962, 1969, 1975, 1976, 1979, 1985, undated (Box 100, Folder 1483)
    - Minutes, 1961 (Box 100, Folder 1484)
    - Newsletter, 1972, 1980-1984 (Box 100, Folder 1485)
    - Programs, 1972, 1975, 1982, undated (Box 100, Folder 1486)
  - American Medical Association, undated (Box 100, Folder 1487)
  - American Orthopsychiatric Association, Inc.
    - Memoranda, undated (Box 100, Folder 1488)
    - Programs, 1954 (Box 100, Folder 1489)
  - American Psychiatric Association
    - Convention Information, 1949, 1969, 1978, 1981 (Box 100, Folder 1490)
    - Newsletters, 1966, 1983 (Box 100, Folder 1491)
    - Newspapers, 1975, 1977, 1981-1983 (Box 100, Folder 1492-1494)
  - American Psychoanalytic Association
    - Memoranda, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 1495)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1962-1985, undated (Box 101, Folder 1496-1504)
    - General Notices, 1971-1973, undated (Box 101, Folder 1505-1506)
    - Board on Professional Standards, 1962, 1963 (Box 101, Folder 1507)
    - Committee on Child Analysis, 1961-1966 (Box 101, Folder 1508-1509)
    - Committee on Psychoanalytic Education, 1965-1967 (Box 101, Folder 1510)
    - Committee on Recognition to Research Graduates of Institutes, 1968-1972 (Box 101, Folder 1511)
    - Committee on Social Problems, 1963, 1969 (Box 102, Folder 1512)
    - Committee on Training for Research, 1969-1973 (Box 102, Folder 1513)
    - Committee on Training Standards in Child Analysis, 1957, 1958, undated (Box 102, Folder 1514)
    - Committee Reports, 1962 (Box 102, Folder 1515)
    - Meeting Notices and Minutes of Coordinating Committee, 1962, 1963 (Box 102, Folder 1516)
    - Conference on Psychoanalytic Education and Research
      - Preparatory Commission on Child Analysis
        - Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 102, Folder 1517-1519)
        - Minutes, 1972, 1973 (Box 102, Folder 1520)
        - Position Paper Drafts-Belmont, Clower, 1973 (Box 102, Folder 1521)
        - Position Paper Drafts-Emde, Harley, Hirschberg, Kramer, 1973 (Box 102, Folder 1522)
        - Position Paper Drafts-Marcus, Nagera, Olch, Robbins, 1973 (Box 102, Folder 1523)
        - Position Paper Drafts-Shane, Weiss, Unidentified, 1973 (Box 102, Folder 1524)
        - Position Paper-Draft, Copy 1, 1973 (Box 103, Folder 1525)
        - Position Paper-Draft, Copy 2, 1973 (Box 103, Folder 1526)
      - The Tripartite System of Psychoanalytic Education-Position Paper (Box 103, Folder 1527)
      - The Ideal Institute-Position Paper, 1974 February (Box 103, Folder 1528)
      - Age and The Psychoanalytic Career, 1974 February (Box 103, Folder 1529)
      - Relationship of Psychoanalysis to Current Changes in Medicine and Psychiatric Education, 1974 February (Box 103, Folder 1530)
      - Psychoanalytic Research-Position Paper, 1974 February (Box 103, Folder 1531)
    - Post-Conference on Psychoanalytic Education and Research
      - Child Analysis Position Paper, 1974 February (Box 103, Folder 1532)
      - Commission on Child Analysis-Correspondence, 1976 (Box 103, Folder 1533)
      - Study Group on Development-Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 103, Folder 1534)
    - Programs
      - Preliminary, 1973, 1980 (Box 103, Folder 1535)
      - Provisional, 1962, 1970, 1981, 1983 (Box 103, Folder 1536)
      - Meetings, 1950-1984 (Box 104, Folder 1537-1539)
    - Roster Supplement, 1974, 1975 (Box 104, Folder 1540)
    - Roster Update and Errata, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 1541)
    - Roster, 1977-1984 (Box 104, Folder 1542-1545)
    - Newsletters, 1962-1983 (Box 104, Folder 1546-1547)
  - American Society for Adolescent Psychiatry
    - Newsletters, 1962-1983 (Box 105, Folder 1548)
    - Programs, 1969 (Box 105, Folder 1549)
  - Association for Child Psychoanalysis, Inc.
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1969-1985, undated (Box 105, Folder 1550)
    - Membership Roster, undated (Box 105, Folder 1551)
    - Minutes, 1969-1975 (Box 105, Folder 1552)
    - Newsletters, 1968-1971 (Box 105, Folder 1553)
    - Programs, 1971-1979 (Box 105, Folder 1554)
  - Council of Psychoanalytic Societies of Greater New York, 1976 (Box 105, Folder 1555)
  - International Association for Child Psychiatry, 1961 (Box 105, Folder 1556)
  - International Psycho-Analytical Association
    - Correspondence, 1979, 1983 (Box 105, Folder 1557)
    - Newsletters, 1973-1983 (Box 105, Folder 1558-1559)
    - Notices, 1969 (Box 105, Folder 1560)
    - Programs
      - Meetings, 1967, 1981 (Box 105, Folder 1561)
      - Preliminary, 1979, 1981 (Box 105, Folder 1562)
      - Provisional, 1969, 1983 (Box 105, Folder 1563)
    - Roster, 1975, 1981 (Box 105, Folder 1564)
  - New York Council on Child Psychiatry
    - Correspondence, 1962-1972, undated (Box 105, Folder 1565)
    - Newsletters, 1962, 1964 (Box 105, Folder 1566)
  - New York Psychoanalytic Society and Institute
    - Correspondence, 1963-1981 (Box 106, Folder 1567-1568)
    - Newsletters, 1968-1984 (Box 106, Folder 1569-1571)
    - Reports, Annual, 1971, 1972 (Box 106, Folder 1572)
  - New York Psychoanalytic Society
    - Board of Directors
      - Correspondence, 1971-1973, undated (Box 106, Folder 1573-1577)
      - Minutes, 1971-1974 (Box 106, Folder 1578-1579)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda
      - General, 1959-1985, undated (Box 107, Folder 1580-1582)
      - Freud Anniversary Lecture, 1971 (Box 107, Folder 1583)
      - Insurance, 1971-1973 (Box 107, Folder 1584)
      - Lewin Memorial, 1972 (Box 107, Folder 1585)
      - Officers, 1972, 1973, undated (Box 107, Folder 1586)
      - Regional Meeting, 1971, 1972 (Box 107, Folder 1587)
      - Research Membership, 1969 (Box 107, Folder 1588)
    - Committees
      - Ad-Hoc Committee on the Subject of Nuclear Weapons, 1962 (Box 107, Folder 1589)
      - Affiliated Societies, 1971, 1972 (Box 107, Folder 1590)
      - Educational Committee, 1971-1975 (Box 107, Folder 1591)
      - Interdisciplinary and Community Affairs, 1972, 1973 (Box 107, Folder 1592)
      - Legal Counsel, 1972, 1973 (Box 107, Folder 1593)
      - Legislation Subcommittee, 1972 (Box 107, Folder 1594)
      - Membership, 1962, 1963 (Box 107, Folder 1595)
      - Nominating, 1972, 1973 (Box 107, Folder 1596)
      - Program, 1971-1973, undated (Box 107, Folder 1597)
    - President's Report, 1971-1985 (Box 107, Folder 1598-1599)
  - New York Psychoanalytic Institute
    - Annual Report of the President, 1959, 1961, 1965 (Box 108, Folder 1600)
    - Board of Trustees, 1961, 1972, 1973 (Box 108, Folder 1601)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda
      - General, 1957-1985, undated (Box 108, Folder 1602-1605)
      - Auxiliary Group, 1974 (Box 108, Folder 1606)
      - Brill Library, 1961-1983 (Box 108, Folder 1607)
    - Committees
      - General, 1959-1983 (Box 108, Folder 1608)
      - Admissions, 1963 (Box 108, Folder 1609)
      - Child Analysis, 1962 (Box 108, Folder 1610)
      - Educational, 1960-1980, undated (Box 108, Folder 1611-1612)
      - Joint, 1969 (Box 108, Folder 1613)
      - Research, 1964 (Box 108, Folder 1614)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1963-1983 (Box 109, Folder 1615-1619)
    - Treatment Center
      - Affiliated Staff Meeting, 1958-1960 (Box 109, Folder 1620)
      - Annual Bulletin, 1959-1979 (Box 109, Folder 1621-1622)
      - Child Analysis Meeting, 1957-1961 (Box 109, Folder 1623-1624)
      - General Correspondence, 1955-1979, undated (Box 110, Folder 1625-1627)
    - Kris Study Group
      - All Sections, 1961-1969 (Box 110, Folder 1628-1634)
      - Arlow Section, 1958-1963 (Box 111, Folder 1635-1639)
      - Beres Section, 1961-1965 (Box 111, Folder 1640-1643)
      - Brenner Section, 1960, 1961 (Box 112, Folder 1644-1645)
      - Lowenstein Section, 1959-1965 (Box 112, Folder 1646-1647)
  - Philadelphia Psychoanalytic Institute
    - Catalogs, 1950-1960 (Box 112, Folder 1648-1649)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda
      - General, 1959-1966 (Box 112, Folder 1650)
      - Child Analysis Seminar, NewYork-Philadelphia, 1957-1961, undated (Box 112, Folder 1651)
    - Committees
      - Child Analysis, 1959-1964 undated (Box 112, Folder 1652)
      - Education, 1957-1960 (Box 112, Folder 1653)
  - Philadelphia Psychoanalytic Society
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1959-1963, 1982 (Box 112, Folder 1654)
    - Committees-Program Committee, 1979, 1980 (Box 112, Folder 1655)
    - Newsletter, 1961, 1979 (Box 112, Folder 1656)
  - Psychoanalytic Association of New York
    - Newsletters, 1972-1985 (Box 112, Folder 1657)
- Awards and Certificates, 1916-1985; Series V; 3 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series is arranged into two subseries: Awards and Certificates. The awards are arranged alphabetically by granting association or institution. The certificates are arranged chronologically and include education, identification, and membership certificates. Oversize awards and certificates are arranged alphabetically within boxes 114 and 115. Medals presented to Mahler are located in box 116.
  - Awards
    - American Academy of Psychoanalysis, 1970 (Box 113, Folder 1658)
    - American Psychiatric Association, 1969 (Box 113, Folder 1659)
    - The Journal of the American Psychiatric Association, 1983 (Box 113, Folder 1660)
    - The Medical Society of the State of New York, 1973 (Box 113, Folder 1661)
  - Certificates
    - Extracts of Birth Certificate, 1907 September 3 (Box 113, Folder 1662)
    - Kiégeszítö Erettségi Bizonyít, 1916 June 27 (Box 113, Folder 1663)
    - Kiégeszitö Erettségi Bizonyít, 1916 June 27 (Box 113, Folder 1664)
    - Leánygimnáziumi Érettségi Bizonyítvány, 1921 November 15 (Box 113, Folder 1665)
    - Budapesti Király Magyar Studomanyeg Yeteum, 1916 September 26 (Box 113, Folder 1666)
    - Universitatis Hungaricae Budapestinesis, 1916-1921 (Box 113, Folder 1667)
    - Universität München, 1920 March 25 (Box 113, Folder 1668)
    - Thuringilche Gesamt-Universitat Jena, 1921, 1923 (Box 113, Folder 1669)
      See also: box 3, folder 65
    - Universität Heidelberg, 1921 July 27 (Box 113, Folder 1670)
    - Universität Wien, 1923 (Box 113, Folder 1671)
    - Certificate of Austrian Citizenship, 1923 April 12 (Box 113, Folder 1672)
    - Orthopádische Klinik, München, 1923 July 20 (Box 113, Folder 1673)
    - Jenaer Kinderklinik-J. Ibrahim, 1925 August 12 (Box 113, Folder 1674)
    - Wirkschaftliche Organisation der Ärtze Wiens, 1926 May 14 (Box 113, Folder 1675)
    - Wiener Jugendhilfswerk, 1926 August 25 (Box 113, Folder 1676)
    - Büro der Verwaltsgruppe III, 1926 September 7 (Box 113, Folder 1677)
    - Magistrat Wien, Abteilung, 1926 October 6, 1930 August 26 (Box 113, Folder 1678)
    - Verinigte Österreich Krankenkaffenhilfe für erholungsbedurftige Kinder, 1929 August 20 (Box 113, Folder 1679)
    - Jugendämtern-A. Aichhorn, 1930 January 31 (Box 113, Folder 1680)
    - Vorstand der Israelische Kultusgemeinde, 1934 January 18 (Box 113, Folder 1681)
    - Certificate of Marriage, 1937 March 23 (Box 113, Folder 1682)
    - Kinderambulatorium Wien, 1938 June 5 (Box 113, Folder 1683)
    - The American Psychoanalytic Association, 1940, 1962 (Box 113, Folder 1684)
    - United States of America, 1944 (Box 113, Folder 1685)
    - American Academy of Child Psychiatry, 1953 (Box 113, Folder 1686)
    - American Psychiatric Association, 1953, 1978 (Box 113, Folder 1687)
    - Colleagues, 1967 (Box 113, Folder 1688)
    - New York City (Department of Health), 1967 (Box 113, Folder 1689)
    - Philadelphia Psychoanalytic Institute Student Organization, 1968 (Box 113, Folder 1690)
    - Medical College of Pennsylvania, 1971 (Box 113, Folder 1691)
    - The New York County Health Service Review Organization, 1976 (Box 113, Folder 1692)
    - The New York Council on Child Psychiatry, Inc., 1978 (Box 113, Folder 1693)
    - Universidad del Salvador, 1979 (Box 113, Folder 1694)
    - The University of the State of New York, 1980, 1982, 1985 (Box 113, Folder 1695)
    - American Medical Association, 1981, 1984, 1985 (Box 113, Folder 1696)
    - The New York Academy of Science, 1983 (Box 113, Folder 1697)
    - The International Psycho-Analytical Association, undated (Box 113, Folder 1698)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 113, Folder 1699)
    - Translations, 1938 (Box 113, Folder 1700)
    - Copy of Jena-doctor diploma (Box 186)
  - Awards
    - Albert Einstein College of Medicine/Yeshiva University, 1975 (Box 114, Folder 1701)
    - Barnard College, 1980 (Box 114, Folder 1702)
    - New York Council on Child Psychiatry: Wilfred C. Hulse Award, 1979 (Box 114, Folder 1703)
    - The New York Psychoanalytic Institute, 1970, 1975 (Box 114, Folder 1704)
    - New York Psychoanalytic Society: A. A. Brill Award, 1962 (Box 114, Folder 1705)
    - The Philadelphia Psychoanalytic Society and the Philadelphia Psychoanalytic Institute, 1967 (Box 114, Folder 1706)
    - Postgraduate Center for Mental Health, 1983 (Box 114, Folder 1707)
    - United Jewish Appeal-Federation of Jewish Philanthropies, 1976 (Box 114, Folder 1708)
  - Certificates
    - Délano, Jack, 1916 June 27 (Box 114, Folder 1709)
    - University of the State of New York Medicine and Surgery License, 1939 (Box 114, Folder 1710)
    - New York Psychoanalytic Society, 1941 (Box 114, Folder 1711)
    - American Board of Psychiatry and Neurology, 1961 (Box 114, Folder 1712)
  - Awards
    - American Psychiatric Association: Distinguished Service Award, 1981 (Box 115, Folder 1713)
    - American Society for Adolescent Psychiatry: William Schonfeld Award, 1983 (Box 115, Folder 1714)
  - Medals(13)
    - American Academy of Child Psychiatry, 1978 (Box 116)
    - American Psychiatric Association, undated (Box 116)
    - Barnard College, 1980 (Box 116)
    - First World Congress of Infant Psychiatry, 1980 (Box 116)
    - August Aichorn (2), undated (Box 116)
    - Paul Federn, undated (Box 116)
    - Sigmund Freud (2), undated (Box 116)
    - Clemens von Pirquet, undated (Box 116)
    - Unidentified (3), undated (Box 116)
    - Albert Einstein College of Medicine - Montefore Medical Center, 1987 (Box 116)
- Photographs, 1890s-1983; Series VI; 6 linear feet (13 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subjects. The material includes black and white, and color prints, as well as negatives, transparencies and slides, which are located at the end of the series.
  - Prints
    - Animals, undated (Box 117, Folder 1715)
    - Artwork, undated (Box 117, Folder 1716)
    - Awards, 1962-1983 (Box 117, Folder 1717)
    - Beagles, 1950-1960 (Box 117, Folder 1718-1719)
    - Children, A-Z, 1924-1984, undated (Box 117, Folder 1720-1731)
    - Children, Unidentified, undated (Box 118, Folder 1732-1744)
    - Conferences
      - First Stockbridge Congress on Child Analysis, 1950 (Box 118, Folder 1745)
      - Menninger Foundation (with Anna Freud), 1962 (Box 118, Folder 1746)
      - Transference Seminar, Philadelphia, 1965 (Box 118, Folder 1747)
      - International Psychoanalytical Congress, 1967 (Box 118, Folder 1747)